Graham Nessler

Software Developer

+1 215-804-7381 (USA)



gness1804@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/gness1804



https://github.com/gness1804



http://www.grahamnessler.com/

Summary

I am a former history professor and published author turned software developer. I am most knowledgeable about React, React Native, Redux, jQuery, and JavaScript (ES6 and ES5), though I have worked with many other technologies, including newer tools such as Electron. I believe that the core purpose of technology is to improve people's lives, and I am continually pushing myself to learn new skills.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, SQL, Java, Bash

Frameworks: React.js. React Native, Redux, Ember, js, Angular.js

Libraries: Redux, ¡Query, Express.js, Sass, HTML5 Canvas, Selenium, Jest, Enzyme,

Mocha, Chai, Electron

Databases: Postgres, Firebase

Office and Design Tools: Sketch, Microsoft Office

IDEs: Atom, Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, Vim, XCode

Other Technical: JSON, Agile, TDD, Git and Github, Webpack, Websockets, Web

Accessibility/ARIA

Human Languages: English, Spanish, French, Brazilian Portuguese

Other Non-Technical: Excellent writing skills, mentoring, teaching, public speaking,

teamwork

Projects

FlashcardFE

April 2017





This app exists to help job seekers prepare for front end developer interviews. From the Home screen, you can select from three categories of questions: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. These in turn are divided by category (typically difficulty). You can use this app to quiz yourself or others. Also, there is a section with links to useful interview-related sites and a section with questions to ask an interviewer. Built in React Native.

MyGov (with Ian Lancaster)

February 2017 - March 2017

MyGov is an application created in React Native that allows a user to track current Congressional bills and new laws. Using the Sunlight Congress API, the application brings in data on bills and laws including title, date introduced, date of last action, sponsor, current progress (in House Committee, passed by Senate, enacted...), and other data. This application is meant for concerned citizens (and noncitizens) to keep track of Congressional actions and to be better informed and empowered to take action on critical issues.

For other projects, see my portfolio.

Experience

Express Scripts / Front End/UI Developer Intern

May 2017-August 2017, Austin, TX

In this position, I will use React.js and other technologies to create user interfaces.

Turing School of Software and Design / Student, Front End Engineering

August 2016-March 2017, Denver, CO

During seven months of intensive work at Turing, I built many projects in JavaScript, React.js, React Native, HTML, CSS, and other technologies.

Florida Atlantic University / Visiting Professor of History

August 2015-May 2016, Boca Raton, FL

In this position, I taught courses in United States, Caribbean, Latin American, and global history to around 200 students.

Education

Turing School of Software and Design / Certificate, Front End Engineering August 2016-March 2017, Denver, CO

University of Michigan / Doctorate in History

September 2005-December 2011, Ann Arbor, MI

College of William and Mary / Bachelors of Arts in History

August 2001-May 2005, Williamsburg, VA